Md Tahmid Chowdhury Abir

Hardware Design Engineer

+8801792615320 tahmidabir2017@gmail.com

> www.github.com/tahmidabir www.linkedin.com/in/tahmidabir

ABOUT ME

A fresh graduate at BRAC University from the department of CSE, currently working as a hardware design engineer at AcciGone. I have more than three years of experience in Robotics and IoT, Software Engineering and also enthusiastic about Machine Learning and Networking. I believe every problem can be solved using technology, hence I try to explore new technologies and technology-based startups.

EDUCATION

2017-2021

BRAC UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering CGPA: 3.72 out of 4

2015-2016

RAJUK UTTARA MODEL COLLEGE

Higher Secondary Certificate (H.S.C.)

GPA: 5.0 out of 5.0

2013-2014

MILESTONE COLLEGE

Secondary School Certificate (S.S.C.) GPA: 5.0 out of 5.0

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Proteus	Quartus
Labview	Cisco Packet Tracer
Arduino IDE	Unity
Webots	Verilog
Fusion 360	Adobe Products

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Hardware

- IOT based System Design
- Robotics
- · Embeded System Design
- PCB Designing

WORK EXPERIENCE

FEB 2022 - PRESENT

Hardware Engineer

AcciGone

- Design, development and production of IoT devices
- Provides subject matter expert level experience in integration
- · Research and Documentation on various electronic components.

2021-2022

Student Tutor

BRAC University

- Provide regular consultancy for Introcution to Robotics course.
- · Help students in making lab projects.
- Help Faculty members in script and assignment checking.

2019-2020

Director

Robotics Club of BRAC University

- Initiate various Robotics projects and assist the club members.
- · Conduct workshops on various topics
- ·Organize national level events

2017-2020

Lead Graphic Designer

Mr.Manik Group Limited

- · Design digital contents for various events
- Food Photography

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software

- · OOP Based Software Designing
- Web Developing
- UI Designing
- · 2D Game Development
- · Graphics Designing
- Video Editing

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORK

- Python
- Django
- · HTML/CSS
- Bootstrap
- · C
- · C#
- Java
- · SQL

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

- Hospital Management System &
- · Railway Management System &
- ATM Machine Management System
- E-Commerce for Farmers
- · Portfolio Websites ₽
- · Company Profile Websites &
- Save life Blood donor finding app
- Verify me Product verification app
- Roar -fire alarm security APP with IOT &
- · 2D Scroller Game
- · 3D Open World Game-Nikkhipto €
- Subnet Converter
- Text Analyzer

 Ø

HARDWARE PROJECTS

- · Humainoid Robot-Simi &
- Underground Heavy Mining Robot Ø
- Industrial Fire Solution @
- Agri Robot- do various agriculture work &
- · Advanced Line Follower &
- · CNC Writing Machine
- CNC Laser Engraving Machine
- Lazy Shark-Battle Bot

 Ø
- · Soccer Bot
- Automatic Water Pump System
- IoT Based fire Alarm and Security System
- · Vehicle Tracking System
- · Home automation with IoT
- · Quad Copter &

REFERENCE

DR. MD. KHALILUR RHAMAN

Associate Professor Department of CSE BRAC UNIVERSITY

Phone: +8801752042223 Email: khalilur@bracu.ac.bd

ACHIEVEMENTS

Finalist, 2nd Runners Up, Robotics Reality Show

Esho Robot Banai - Channel i, 2019 Bangladesh's first ever Robotics Reality show

Vice Chancellor's Certificate-Spring 2018

Residential Semester BRAC University

2nd Runners Up, Entrepreneurship Competition

Megapreneurs 2.0,2020 YSI Bangladesh Limited

Champion, Mobile App Development Contest

IUT 10th ICT Fest 2019

Islamic University of Technology

1st Runners Up, Project Showcasing

Bitfest 2019

Khulna University of Engineering & Technology

1st Runners Up, Robo Wrestling

Robotronics 2019

Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology

2nd And 3rd Prize in Lifestyle Photography

Naturenlight-2016

Rajuk Uttara Model College

RESEARCH & ONGOING WORKS

- Personalization in Federated Recommendation System using SVD++ with Explainability
- UV Disinfection Robot
- · Theoretical Research on Responsible AI
- · IoT in RMG Supply Chain
- Automation of IoT based Warehouse Management System
- IoT Based Live Blackbox for Vehicle Monitoring and Data Aanalysis to Prevent Road Accidents

PUBLISHED PAPER

 Detection of Covid-19 Affected Patients from CT Scan Image of Lungs Dataset using Federated Learning with Explainable AI

(IAICT,2022)